[
    {
        "subject" : "Operating System",
        "question" : "Which of the following is not an operating system?",
        "option1" : "Windows",
        "option2" : "Linux",
        "option3" : "Oracle",
        "option4" : "DOS",
        "answer" : "Oracle"
    },
    {
        "subject" : "Operating System",
        "question" : "What is the maximum length of the filename in DOS?",
        "option1" : "4",
        "option2" : "5",
        "option3" : "8",
        "option4" : "12",
        "answer" : "8"
    },
    {
        "subject" : "Operating System",
        "question" : "When was the first operating system developed?",
        "option1" : "1948",
        "option2" : "1949",
        "option3" : "1950",
        "option4" : "1951",
        "answer" : "1950"
    },
    {
        "subject" : "Operating System",
        "question" : "When were MS windows operating systems proposed?",
        "option1" : "1994",
        "option2" : "1990",
        "option3" : "1992",
        "option4" : "1985",
        "answer" : "1985"
    },
    {
        "subject" : "Operating System",
        "question" : "Which of the following is the extension of Notepad?",
        "option1" : ".txt",
        "option2" : ".xls",
        "option3" : ".ppt",
        "option4" : ".bmp",
        "answer" : ".txt"
    },
    {
        "subject" : "Operating System",
        "question" : "What else is a command interpreter called?",
        "option1" : "prompt",
        "option2" : "kernel",
        "option3" : "shell",
        "option4" : "command",
        "answer" : "shell"
    },
    {
        "subject" : "Operating System",
        "question" : "What is the full name of FAT?",
        "option1" : "File attribute table",
        "option2" : "File allocation table",
        "option3" : "Font attribute table",
        "option4" : "Format allocation table",
        "answer" : "File allocation table"
    },
    {
        "subject" : "Operating System",
        "question" : "BIOS is used?",
        "option1" : "By operating system",
        "option2" : "By compiler",
        "option3" : "By interpreter",
        "option4" : "By application software",
        "answer" : "By operating system"
    },
    {
        "subject" : "Operating System",
        "question" : "What is the mean of the Booting in the operating system?",
        "option1" : "Restarting computer",
        "option2" : "Install the program",
        "option3" : "To scan",
        "option4" : "To turn off",
        "answer" : "Restarting computer"
    },
    {
        "subject" : "Operating System",
        "question" : "When does page fault occur?",
        "option1" : "The page is present in memory.",
        "option2" : "The deadlock occurs.",
        "option3" : "The page does not present in memory.",
        "option4" : "The buffering occurs.",
        "answer" : "The page does not present in memory."
    },
    {
        "subject" : "Operating System",
        "question" : "Banker's algorithm is used?",
        "option1" : "To prevent deadlock",
        "option2" : "To deadlock recovery",
        "option3" : "To solve the deadlock",
        "option4" : "None of these",
        "answer" : "To prevent deadlock"
    },
    {
        "subject" : "Operating System",
        "question" : "When you delete a file in your computer, where does it go?",
        "option1" : "Recycle bin",
        "option2" : "Hard disk",
        "option3" : "Taskbar",
        "option4" : "None of these",
        "answer" : "Recycle bin"
    },
    {
        "subject" : "Operating System",
        "question" : "Which is the Linux operating system?",
        "option1" : "Private operating system",
        "option2" : "Windows operating system",
        "option3" : "Open-source operating system",
        "option4" : "None of these",
        "answer" : "Open-source operating system"
    },
    {
        "subject" : "Operating System",
        "question" : "What is the full name of the DSM?",
        "option1" : "Direct system module",
        "option2" : "Direct system memory",
        "option3" : "Demoralized system memory",
        "option4" : "Distributed shared memory",
        "answer" : "Distributed shared memory"
    },
    {
        "subject" : "Operating System",
        "question" : "What is the full name of the IDL?",
        "option1" : "Interface definition language",
        "option2" : "Interface direct language",
        "option3" : "Interface data library",
        "option4" : "None of these",
        "answer" : "Interface definition language"
    }
]